<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>kafka on imalik8088</title>
    <link>https://imalik8088.de/tags/kafka/</link>
    <description>Recent content in kafka on imalik8088</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2022 09:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://imalik8088.de/tags/kafka/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Kafka, where are all my messages 😱?</title>
      <link>https://imalik8088.de/posts/kafka_where_are_all_my_messages/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2022 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imalik8088.de/posts/kafka_where_are_all_my_messages/</guid>
      <description>Recently I got the chance to help a customer moving from a Helm based deployment of Apache Kafka in Kubernetes to the Strimzi, which manages the deployment of Kafka in Kubernetes with an operator. In the final phase, I had to transfer the data to the newly deployed Apache Kafka.
Setting the scope The customer is using compacted topics (cleanup.policy=compact and log.rentention.ms=-1) as the default configuration for all topics in Apache Kafka, so they&amp;rsquo;re using it somehow like a database where messages are produced with an unique ID and are nulled afterwards when it is required to delete a message.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ETL with Kafka</title>
      <link>https://imalik8088.de/posts/etl-with-kafka/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2018 23:08:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imalik8088.de/posts/etl-with-kafka/</guid>
      <description>Originally published at codecentrics blog
&amp;ldquo;ETL with Kafka&amp;rdquo; is a catchy phrase that I purposely chose for this post instead of a more precise title like &amp;ldquo;Building a data pipeline with Kafka Connect&amp;rdquo;.
TLDR You don’t need to write any code for pushing data into Kafka, instead just choose your connector and start the job with your necessary configurations. And it’s absolutely Open Source!
Kafka Connect Kafka Before getting into the Kafka Connect framework, let us briefly sum up what Apache Kafka is in couple of lines.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
